자막제작 - 네이트 CSI 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/clubcsi)
Mommy, up.
엄마, 안아줘
Up, mommy, up.
안아줘, 엄마, 안아줘
Not now, baby, mommy's busy.
지금은 안 돼, 엄마는 바빠
Go find daddy.
아빠한테 가봐
Honey, I cannot find my navy suit.
여보, 감색 양복이 안 보여
Oh, I'm sorry, shoot.
오, 정말 미안해요
I meant to get it this morning, but
오늘 아침에 찾아오려고 했는데
Henry was doing his ear itchy thing,
so I took him to Dr. Neilsen.
헨리가 귀를 가려워해서
병원에 데려가느라 못 찾아왔어요
I'll get it first thing tomorrow.
내일 아침 일찍 찾아올게요
Oh, I have an early meeting, sweetie.
아침 일찍 회의가 있어, 여보
So go get it.
그럼 가서 찾아와요
Oh... all right.
알았어
Daddy, no leave.
아빠, 가지 마
Aw... daddy no leave.
오... 아빠 가지 마
You give him a bath, I'll go.
헨리 목욕 좀 시켜줘요
내가 갈 테니까
Welcome to LVRP, rat pack radio.
라스베가스 랫팩 라디오입니다
Here's an oldie but a goodie
by two salty dogs of stage and screen,
오늘은 무대와 영화의 두 명의 해적
바비 달린과 조니 머서가 부른
Bobby Darin and Johnny Mercer.
흘러간 좋은 노래를 보내드립니다
Two of a kind, for your information,
we're two of a kind.
너무 닮았어요, 모르시나 본데
우린 너무 닮았어요
Like Peas in a pod, and birds
of a feather-alone or together,
콩깍지 속에 콩처럼, 같은 깃털을
가진 새처럼 - 혼자이든 함께든
That we are two-oo-oo,
oo-oo-oo, oo-oo-oo, oo of a kind
우린 너무~ 닮았어요
Who's to say if we're
goin' the whole way?
우리가 영원히 함께 할지 아닐지
누가 알겠어요?
At least we got this far
적어도 지금까진 함께했죠
Sharin' our lives, our vittles,
and viands, we're two of an ilk
함께 살고, 똑같은 음식을 먹으면서
우린 너무 닮았어요~
Say, what if we've got rare
Chateaubriands or crackers and milk?
우리에게 진귀한 비프 스테이크나
과자랑 우유가 생기면 어떻게 할까요?
Makin' it plain, Explainin' it fully
쉽고 자세하게 설명해 줄 거예요
We're similarly inclined, because
우린 좋아하는 것도 똑같아요
we're two-oo-oo, oo-oo-oo,
oo-oo-oo, oo of a kind
우리 너무~ 너무~ 닮았으니까요
Bad day when you can't
even run a simple errand.
요즘은 간단한 심부름도
무서워서 못하겠군요
Everybody's got dirty laundry.
누구나 빨래는 해야 하지
Sometimes it gets you killed.
빨래 때문에
죽어야 할 때도 있군
What would she have done if
she didn't have a second story?
만약에 이 층(story)이 없었다면
어떻게 했을까요?
Every death has at least two stories.
모든 죽음에는 적어도 두 가지의
이야기(story)가 있기 마련이야
딕테이션
전상진(thelastdayofschool@nate.com)
싱크편집
송미혜(smh8119@nate.com)
한글번역
이현정(ayanokosikyo@nate.com)
월리암 피터슨(길 그리섬 役)
CSI 레벨3(반장), 전문분야: 곤충학
마그 헬겐버거(캐서린 윌로우스 役)
CSI 레벨3, 전문분야: 혈흔 분석
게리 도단(워릭 브라운 役)
CSI 레벨3, 전문분야: 음향/시각 자료분석
조지 이즈(닉 스톡스 役)
CSI 레벨3, 전문분야: 머리카락, 섬유질 분석
조자 폭스(새라 사이들 役)
CSI 레벨3, 전문분야: 물질성분 분석
에릭 스즈맨다(그렉 샌더스 役)
CSI 레벨1, 전문분야: DNA분석
로버트 데이비드 홀(알 로빈스 役)
검시관, 전문분야: 법의학
루이스 롬바드(소피아 커티스 役)
라스베가스시 경찰청 형사
폴 길포일(짐 브래스 役)
라스베가스시 경찰청 경감
CSI: Crime Scene Investigation
7x08 Happenstance
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON CBS: 2006/11/16
Two gsws to the chest.
Rigor hasn't set.
가슴에 총상이 두 개 있어요
사후 경직은 아직 오지 않았으니까
Probably been dead
less than four hours.
사망한 지 4시간도 채
안 된 것 같아요
Thanks, David.
고마워, 데이빗
Mr. Chen works here
alone with his wife,
첸 씨는 여기서 아내랑
단둘이서 일한대요
and English is not their first language.
영어가 모국어가 아니에요
I'm not even real sure
that it's their second,
심지어 제 2언어조차도
아닌 것 같더군요
but what I did gather is that the
steam machines are very noisy,
하지만, 증기 기계가
소음이 너무 심해서
so neither one of them
really heard anything.
두 사람 모두 아무 소리도
못 들었다는 말은 알아들었어요
Mr. Chen found the body when
he was closing up around 9:00.
첸 씨가 9시쯤에 가게 문을
닫다가 시체를 발견했고
Said she's a regular customer.
피해자가 단골손님이었다군요
Well, I got a phone and keys,
but no purse.
음, 전화랑 열쇠는 있는데
핸드백은 안 보여
Mugging?
노상강도일까요?
Take the purse, leave the Lexus?
핸드백을 가져가고
차는 놔두고 간다고?
Yeah, that's not real savvy, is it?
네, 그랬다면 세상물정 모르는 놈인 거죠
Car's been keyed.
누군가 차를 긁었어
Registered to a Dr. Gary Sinclair.
차주는 게리 싱클레어 박사야
Yeah, that's gonna
probably be the husband.
네, 아마도 피해자 남편인가 봐요
"Gary Home" has called her
six times in the last hour.
지난 1시간 동안 "게리 집"에서
6번이나 전화가 걸려왔군요
Wife and mother.
아내이자 엄마였군
I'll check the trash cans for the complex,
단지 내에 있는
쓰레기통을 조사할게요
see if I can find her purse.
지갑을 찾을 수 있나 보게요
Maybe they dumped
what they couldn't liquidate.
팔 수 없는 건
버렸을 수도 있으니까요
Well, she obviously doesn't have any kids.
이 여자, 확실히 아이는 없겠어요
Place is like a museum.
집안이 박물관 같아요
This chick hung out with some big wigs.
거물들이랑 어울렸네요
She was a big wig.
이 여자가 거물이었어
Jill Case, editor in
chief of the Las Vegas Globe.
질 케이스, 라스베가스
글로브지의 편집국장이야
She was a wonder kid.
시대의 총아였어
One of the youngest women in
history to run a newspaper.
역사상 신문사를 운영한
가장 어린 여성중 한 명이었거든
Well, I've been all around the house,
no sign of a forced entry.
이 집 주변을 샅샅이 살펴봤는데
강제로 침입한 흔적은 없었어
- Consistent with suicide.
- So is this.
- 자살과 일치하네요
- 이것도요
You can't even use a whole sheet
of paper for your suicide note?
- 모두에게 죄송합니다 -
유서를 쓸 때 종이 한 장을 통째로
다 쓰면 안 되는 건가요?
Well, I don't know, maybe if you feel like
글쎄, 아마도 이 세상에서
you don't deserve to take
up space on the planet,
살 자격이 없다고
생각했다면
you don't deserve a whole piece of paper.
종이 한 장도 다 쓸 자격이 없다고
느꼈을 수 있을 거야
She obviously ate at Joie de Vive.
분명히 조아 드 비브에서
식사를 했을 거예요
It's the only place that still serves
old school swan doggie bags.
이렇게 구식 백조 모양으로 남은 음식을
포장해 주는 곳은 거기뿐이거든요
Yeah, dressed in a fancy outfit,
having a fancy meal.
그래, 화려하게 차려입고
멋진 식사를 했겠지
If you're planning on killing yourself,
만약에 자살하기로 결심했다면
why do you bring home a doggie bag?
왜 남은 음식을 싸왔을까요?
It's human nature.
인간의 본성이야
We continue to perform the
routine motions of our life
우린 죽는 바로 그 순간까지도
until the moment of our death.
삶의 일상적인 행위들을
멈추질 않거든
다시는 나한테 연락하지 말아요 - 도라
DNA's been sent out,
DNA 샘플을 보내긴 했지만
but this is one case where
I don't need to wait for results.
이번엔 결과를 기다릴
필요도 없겠어
Identical twins?
일란성 쌍둥이예요?
You got to be kidding me.
어이가 없군요
They're even wearing
the same toenail polish.
발톱에 바른 매니큐어도
같은 색깔이에요
And both wore the same watch, too.
게다가 둘 다
같은 시계를 차고 있었어
Oh, it's just too much.
오, 그건 좀 심하네요
Well...
그게...
Eight year olds dressing alike
I kind of get, but grown women?
8살짜리 애들이 같은 옷을 입은 건
이해가 되지만, 성인 여성들이 그런다면?
- That's weird.
- Some people like it.
- 이상해요
- 어떤 사람들은 좋아해
I'm a twin. / Really?
나도 쌍둥이야 / 정말이에요?
Well, was.
My twin died in utero.
음, 쌍둥이였지
내 쌍둥이는 뱃속에서 죽었거든
My mother didn't tell me
about it until I was an adult.
어머니는 내가 어른이 될 때까지
말씀해 주지 않으셨어
When I decided to become a coroner,
she blamed herself.
내가 검시관이 되려고 결심했을 때
어머니는 자신을 탓하시더군
She said it was because I'd spent so
many days living next to a dead body.
내가 시체 곁에서 너무 많은 시간을
보내서 그렇다고 말야
Well, speaking of
dead bodies... / Right.
- 시체 얘기가 나와서 말인데요
- 알겠네
Right. Jill has petechia around the eyes,
bruising around the neck,
질은 눈 주변에 점상 출혈
목 주변에 멍이 있고
and a broken clavicle.
All consistent with a hanging.
쇄골도 부러졌고
모두 목을 맨 거랑 일치하지
And I extracted these from Amanda.
그리고 이것들은
아만다에게서 꺼낸 거야
One went straight to the heart.
The other penetrated the right lung.
하나는 곧장 심장에 박혔고
다른 하나는 오른쪽 폐를 관통했어
Sharp shooter or close range.
명사수거나
가까이서 쐈겠지
Don't tell me they died
at the same moment.
설마 둘이 동시에
죽은 건 아니겠죠?
Not quite. Amanda was a
couple hours ahead of her sister.
그렇진 않아. 아만다가
몇 시간 더 일찍 죽었어
Our two cases have become one.
두 사건이 하나가 됐어요
Could still be two cases.
여전히 두 사건일 수도 있지
What happened to Mr. No
such thing as coincidence?
'우연 같은 건 없다' 씨에게
무슨 일이 생긴 거예요?
Simplest hypothesis is
usually the correct one.
가장 단순한 가설이 대개
올바른 가설이다
If you hear hooves,
think horses not zebras.
말발굽 소리를 들으면, 얼룩말이
아니라 말이라고 생각해라
What would the horses be in this case?
이 사건에서 말이 뭐지?
Murder, suicide.
살인 후 자살이요
Jill killed Amanda.
질이 아만다를 죽였고
Felt guilty, then killed herself.
죄책감을 느껴서
자살한 거죠
What do you got to support that?
무슨 근거로
그렇게 생각하지?
Did you notice any photos of Amanda
or her family in Jill's house?
질의 집에서 아만다나
아만다의 가족사진 보신 적 있으세요?
No. / Right.
아니 / 좋아요
And I looked through Amanda's
phone book, Jill was not even in it.
아만다의 전화 번호부를 봤는데
질은 그 안에 있지도 않았어요
Well, maybe she had her
number memorized.
아만다가 질의 번호를
외우고 있었을지도 모르지
Brass spoke with Jill's
attorney for next of kin.
브래스 경감님이 질의 변호사와
상속인 얘기를 하셨다는데요
None existed.
아무도 없었대요
She's leaving a small
fortune to various charities.
질은 얼마 안 되는 재산을
다양한 자선단체에 기부했대요
It just sounds to me like estrangement.
제가 보기에 서로
다툰 거 같아요
Okay, even if that's not
the exact way it went down,
좋아요, 그게 정확한
사건의 발단이 아니더라도
I'll bet you a dollar that the
twins deaths are related.
두 쌍둥이의 죽음이 연관돼
있다는 것에 1달러 걸겠어요
Two women found dead
on opposite sides of town.
두 여성이 시내의 정반대편에서
시체로 발견됐어
If they didn't look alike,
would you still link them?
그 두 사람이 닮지 않았어도
서로 연관지을 텐가?
If they're relatives, yes.
만약 친척이라면, 그래요
Sisters, husband and wife,
father and son.
자매, 남편과 아내
아버지와 아들이라면요
Okay.
좋아
Okay, what?
좋다니, 뭐가요?
I'll take the bet.
내기를 받아들인다고
Amanda
아만다
I must've called her ten times,
then after about an hour I got so worried.
아내에게 10번도 넘게 전화했을 겁니다
한 시간 정도 지나고 나니 걱정이 됐어요
Did your wife have any enemies?
Anyone she was fighting with?
부인께 적이 있었나요?
다투신 분이라도요?
No, she was a good wife, great mother.
아뇨, 좋은 아내이자
훌륭한 엄마였어요
- There's no one...
- Home, daddy, home.
- 아무도 없어요...
- 집에 가자, 아빠, 집에
Okay, buddy. Can you, hey,
you know what? Come over here.
알았다, 얘야. 있잖아
이리로 오렴
Can you come over here and draw
your butterfly that you draw?
이리로 와서 네가 잘 그리는
나비 그려볼래?
What was her relationship like with Jill?
질과 부인의 관계는 어땠나요?
Jill who?
질 누구요?
Her twin sister, Jill Case.
부인의 쌍둥이 자매
질 케이스 말이에요
Amanda didn't have a sister.
아만다에게는 자매가 없어요
DNA tells us otherwise.
DNA 결과는 다르더군요
My wife was an only child left.
제 아내는 외동딸이었어요
She was adopted, but...
아만다는 입양됐지만...
is it possible that...
혹시 말인데요...
your wife knew she had a twin,
but she hadn't told you?
부인께서 쌍둥이 자매가 있다는 걸 알고
계셨지만, 말씀 안 했을 수도 있을까요?
Well, I'd like to think no.
그랬을 거란 생각은 안 들어요
That we told each other everything.
우린 서로에게
모든 걸 얘기했어요
But that's not... / True?
- 그러나 그건...
- 사실이 아니라고요?
A marriage.
결혼이란 게요
Married, detective?
결혼하셨나요, 형사님?
No.
아뇨
Something weird happens between two
people who know each other for years,
오랫동안 서로 알고 지내 온 두 사람에게
정말 이상한 일이 생겼는데
see each other every day.
매일 얼굴을 맞대고 살아야해요
Every night, I drive home from the hospital
매일 밤, 병원에서 집에 가는 길에
and I think of 12 things
I want to tell Amanda.
아만다에게 말해주고 싶은
12가지 얘깃거리를 생각해내죠
And then I get home and she's cooking.
그리고 나서 집에 오면
아만다는 요리를 하고 있어요
And we read stories to Henry
and then...the phone rings,
우리가 헨리에게 책을 읽어주고나면
전화가 오는 겁니다
so I, you know, you say,
"oh, I'll just tell her tomorrow. Tomorrow."
그래서, 전 이렇게 맘을 먹죠
"오, 내일 얘기하지 뭐, 내일"
I'd like to meet her.
그 여자를 만나고 싶군요
Jill.
질이요
I'm sorry that's...
유감입니다만, 그건...
That's not possible.
We found them both.
불가능해요. 저희가
확인한 바로는, 두 분 모두...
Last night.
지난 밤에요
What happened?
무슨 일이 생긴 거죠?
Right now,
지금 당장은
we don't know.
저희도 모릅니다
It's okay, daddy.
Let's go home and see mommy. / Okay.
괜찮아, 아빠
엄마 보러 집에 가자 / 그래
Hey. I got your text.
What's up?
문자 받았어요
뭐예요?
Sing it, dude.
This is huge. / Oh...
노래해요. 이거 아주
큰 거예요 / 오...
Oh, Mandy oh, you came and you...
오, 맨디, 내게로 와서
당신은...
Oh, Mandy well,
오, 맨디
you came and you gave without taking
내게로 와서 받는 것 없이
당신은 주기만 했죠
but I sent you away.
그런데 당신을 떠나보냈어요
Oh, Mandy.
오, 맨디
Okay. I got a hit off of that envelope
you found in Amanda's purse.
좋아요. 아만다의 핸드백 안에 있던
봉투에서 일치하는 지문을 찾았어요
It's a Dora Pomerantz.
도라 포머란츠 씨예요
Oh, that would make sense.
The letter was signed Dora.
오, 딱 맞아떨어지네요
그 편지에 도라라고 쓰여 있었거든요
Do you wanna know why
she's in the system?
왜 이 여자 지문이 등록되어
있는지 궁금하지 않아요?
Mrs. Pomerantz?
포머란츠 부인?
Who wants to know?
누구신가요?
Detective Curtis and CSI Nick Stokes.
커티스 형사입니다
이쪽은 과학수사대 닉 스톡스고요
Hi. / We just need to
ask you a few questions.
안녕하세요 / 몇 가지
질문을 드리러 왔습니다
About what? / Your twins.
- 무슨 질문요?
- 부인의 쌍둥이에 대해서요
That was a very long time ago.
그건 아주 오래전 일인데요
We were just curious about the circumstances
under which they were adopted.
쌍둥이들이 입양될 당시의
상황을 알고 싶습니다
I was 18 years old when I got pregnant.
임신했을 때 저는
열여덟 살이었어요
Charlie said he'd stay with me.
찰리는 제 곁에 있어주겠다고
약속했었는데
Then he got drafted to Vietnam.
베트남으로 징병 되어 버렸죠
Came home six months later in a box.
여섯 달 뒤에
관에 실려 돌아왔어요
These two chirping birds.
두 쌍둥이는 새처럼 울어댔죠
"Waa, waa, waa."
"응애, 응애, 응애"
I couldn't get them to stop.
울음을 그치게 할 수가 없었어요
I couldn't take it.
참을 수 없었죠
So one day I just.
그래서 어느 날, 그냥
Boop, snapped.
확, 폭발한 거죠
That was it. No more babies.
그게 다예요
애들은 더 이상 없었어요
I spent ten years in a
state facility, you know?
주립 정신 병원에서
10년을 보냈죠
We were aware.
알고 있습니다
How have you been since?
그 후에는 어떻게 지내셨나요?
Oh... fine.
오... 잘 지냈어요
A smart doctor put me in touch
with an equine assisted therapy program.
영리한 의사가 말을 이용한 치료
프로그램에 저를 소개해 줬어요
Saved my life.
내 인생을 구했죠
Horses don't have judgments.
말들은 판단력이 없어요
They have needs.
Meet the needs, the horse is happy.
요구하는 것이 있고
그 요구만 들어주면, 말은 행복해요
Helped retrain my brain.
제가 회복하는 데
도움이 됐어요
Healthy enough to get back in
touch with your daughters?
따님들과 연락할 만큼
회복하신 건가요?
Oh, no.
오, 아뇨
Not recommended.
그건 권하지 않더군요
Sometimes you just can't go back.
때론 되돌릴 수 없는 일도 있어요
Is that why you wrote
Amanda this letter saying,
그래서 아만다에게 이런
편지를 보내신 겁니까?
"please do not ever contact me again?"
"다시는 연락하지 마라"라고요?
Who's Amanda?
아만다가 누구죠?
One of your daughters.
따님들 중에 한 명입니다
We keep envelopes
loose in a desk drawer.
우린 책상 서랍에 편지들을
던져두거든요
I must've touched it before she sent it.
그 애가 보내기 전에
제가 만졌나 봐요
Who?
그 애요?
The handwriting, it's Tiffany's.
글씨가 티파니 글씨네요
I'm sorry. Who's Tiffany?
죄송합니다
티파니가 누구죠?
I had no idea my mom had given up a kid.
전 엄마가 아이를 입양시킨 적이
있다는 걸 몰랐어요
But I did know that there was no way
그래도 엄마가 이런 일을
감당할 수 없었을 거란 건
she could handle dealing with it.
확실히 알고 있었죠
So... you always go
through your mom's mail?
그럼... 항상 어머님의 편지를
살펴보시는 건가요?
Yeah. My dad and I have a system.
네. 아빠와 제게는
방침이 있어요
We screen all her mail.
엄마한테 오는 편지는
전부 읽어봐요
Why's that?
왜 그러시나요?
She's got this problem.
엄마한테는 문제가 있어요
Any time a children's
charity solicitation comes,
어린이 자선단체에서 기부를
원하는 편지가 오기라도 하면
she donates and not just a little.
언제나 기부를 하시거든요
그것도 그냥 조금이 아니에요
Half my college fund was gone
before we realized what was going on.
무슨 일이 일어났는지 알아채기도 전에
제 대학등록금 예금 절반이 사라졌어요
So you thought Amanda
had her hand out?
그러니까 아만다가 돈을
바랐다고 생각했군요
Wasn't worth the risk.
위험을 무릅쓸 수는 없었어요
The anti depressants and the horses help,
항우울제랑 말이
도움이 되긴 하지만
but my mom's barely hanging on.
엄마는 겨우 버티는 중이거든요
And I only have a year
left before I go to college.
그리고 제가 대학에 가기 전까지
딱 일 년 남았고요
I just need her to hang
on one more year.
엄마가 일 년만 더 버텨주시길
바랄 뿐이에요
So, I sent the polite response
and hoped it was over.
그래서, 정중한 편지를 보내고
그게 마지막이길 바란 거죠
Did Jill ever try to contact your mom?
질도 어머니께 연락을 했나요?
Who's Jill?
질이 누군데요?
So I got a bad news and a weird news.
나쁜 소식과 이상한 소식이 있어요
Which would you like to hear first?
어느 걸 먼저 듣고 싶으세요?
Bad. / Bad news:
- 나쁜 것부터
- 나쁜 건요
I got nothing from the blue stocking
that was found in the trash.
그 쓰레기통에서 찾은 파란색
스타킹에선 아무것도 안 나왔어요
Weird news: I tested the red lipstick
on Gary Sinclair's collar and I got DNA,
이상한 결과는, 게리 싱클레어의 옷깃에
묻은 립스틱의 DNA를 검사했는데요
but it wasn't his wife's.
아만다의 것이 아니었어요
Well, based on the contents of her purse,
she's more the lip balm type.
가방에 있던 내용물로 보자면 부인은
립밤(챕스틱)을 사용하던 사람이었어
You know I like to be thorough, so...
제가 좀 철저한 걸 좋아하잖아요
그래서...
I ran it through CODIS and I actually got a hit.
그걸 CODIS에 돌렸는데
결과가 나왔어요
Natal Peled.
나탈 펠렛
She's in the system from a rape charge in L.A.
L.A에서 강간 혐의로 등록됐더라고요
They don't put victim's DNA in the database.
피해자 DNA는 등록 안 하잖아
No, they don't.
네, 그렇죠
Yeah, I had to know, so I called a friend
of mine at L.A. Sheriff's department,
궁금해서 L.A 경찰서에 있는
제 친구에게 전화해봤는데요
and apparently, Natal was a
nurse at a Hollywood Hostal.
분명히, 나탈은 할리우드
병원의 간호사였대요
And she went to the annual Christmas party,
그리고 매년 열리는
크리스마스 파티에 가서
she fed this doctor a bunch of cocktails,
의사에게 칵테일을
잔뜩 마시게 하고
slipped him a prevalis,
and then took him up to a hotel room.
프리발리스를 몰래 타 먹이고
호텔 방으로 데려갔대요
And rumor has it,
it was in order to have unprotected,
그리고 소문에는요
피임을 하지 않은 채로
you know, baby-making sex.
아기를 임신하기 위한
섹스를 했다는군요
So he pressed charges,
she was arrested,
그래서 그 의사가 고소를 했고
나탈은 체포됐어요
and then they settled out of court.
그리고 법정에 가기 전에
합의를 봤대요
And now Natal's a nurse
at our very own dessert palm.
지금 나탈은 바로 여기 데저트 팜에서
간호사로 일하고 있어요
With Amanda's husband, Dr. Gary Sinclair?
아만다의 남편, 게리 싱클레어 씨와 같이?
Doctors have a name for what Natal is.
의사들이 나탈을 가리켜
부르는 말이 있죠
What she is?
그게 뭔데요?
A woman who trolls hospitals
looking to land themselves a doctor.
병원을 전전하면서 정착할 의사를
낚아보려고 몸을 함부로 놀리는 여자죠
Call them bedpans.
그런 여자들을 요강이라고 해요
Shiny, full of crap, and best when dumped.
반짝이고, 오물로 가득차 있고
그리고 버릴 때 기분이 최고거든요
Of course we slept together.
물론 같이 잤죠
Who wouldn't want to get with this?
저 같은 여자랑 자는 걸
누가 마다하겠어요?
Of course he's gonna deny it
because of that little wife of his.
물론 그 사람이야 아내 때문에
부정할 테지만요
So you met his wife, Amanda?
그럼 부인을 만나신 건가요?
아만다를요?
Please, yes, I've met her.
그럼요, 만났어요
Always coming by the hospital,
check up on him.
게리를 감시하려고 항상
병원에 들렀는걸요
Talk about paranoid.
의부증의 화신이었죠
Hey, with you around,
이봐요, 당신이 주위에 어정거리면
sounds like she had pretty good reason.
아만다는 그럴 만한
이유가 있어보이는데요
Mr. Stokes.
스톡스 요원
Men are like tigers.
남자들은 호랑이 같아요
If you can't tame them,
you must let them roam free.
남자를 길들이지 못한다면
그냥 자유로이 돌아다니게 해야 해요
I go now, yeah?
난 이제 갑니다, 알았죠?
Yes. It seems that the paint
네. 그 이스라엘 여자의 열쇠에 있던
on the Sabra's key
is consistent with Lexus factory issue.
페인트가 렉서스 제품과 일치했어요
Color's galactic grey mica ie9.
색깔은 은하 회색 운모 IE9호예요
Same as Amanda's.
아만다 차랑 같네요
So, crazy chick keys the wife's car.
그러니까, 미친 아가씨가
부인의 자동차를 긁은 거군요
Is it gateway violence that led to murder,
살인이 되어버린 현관 폭력일까요?
(현관 폭력 :가정, 여성에 대한 폭력)
or just another coincidence like
everything else in this case?
이 사건의 다른 것들처럼
그냥 우연일까요?
I almost keyed a car once.
한 번은 거의 차를
긁을 뻔했어요
You what?
뭘 했다고요?
I know, but, in the end,
I couldn't go through with it.
나도 알아요, 그런데
결국엔 못했어요
So I peed on the door handles instead.
그래서 대신 문 손잡이에다
오줌을 쌌죠
So they'd freeze up
and can't get them open?
얼어붙게 해서
문을 못 열게 하려고요?
No. It was San Diego.
그건 아니에요
샌 디에고였거든요
Over a girl?
여자 때문에요?
Over a B.
B 때문에요
Professor gave me one on my term paper.
교수가 학기말 리포트에
B를 줬거든요
I felt I deserved an A.
내 생각엔 A를 받아 마땅했는데요
So she definitely keyed the car,
나탈이 차를 긁은 건
확실하지만
and may or may not have
been doing the husband.
게리랑 잤을 수도 있고
안 잤을 수도 있어요
I'm going with yes.
난 잤을 거라 생각해
Ballistics came back on the
bullets that killed Amanda.
아만다에게서 나온 총알의
탄도분석 결과가 나왔어
There's only one gun with a six right
polygonal barrel that comes in a .41 caliber.
41구경을 발사할 만한 6조 우선의
총신은 하나밖에 없대
A Baby Eagle, Israeli military issue.
이스라엘 군에서 제작한 베이비이글이야
Israeli guns are really hard to find.
이스라엘제 총은 구하기 어렵잖아요
Unless you served in the
Israeli army like Natal.
나탈처럼 이스라엘에서
군복무를 하지 않았다면 말이지
Okay. Okay, I certainly
wouldn't put it past her,
좋아요. 나탈은 분명히 그러고도
남을 여자라고 생각되지만
but what about the husband?
남편은 과연 그랬을까요?
Classic "he said, she said."
전형적인 "서로 떠넘기기" 수법이지
They're either acting in cahoots,
trying to confuse us,
둘이 짜고서 범행하고선
우릴 헷갈리게 하려는 것이든지
or natal is acting on her own,
아님, 나탈이 단독으로
범행한 걸 거야
thinking that the wife is the
obstacle standing between them.
아만다가 게리와 자신 사이의
장애물이라고 생각해서 말이야
Nothing quite says "I love you" like,
"당신과 함께하려고 당신 아내를 죽였어"는
"I killed your wife so we can be together."
"당신을 사랑해요"의 최상급 표현이죠
Sir we have a warrant to
search the premises,
선생님, 자택과 소유지에 대한
영장이 나왔습니다
and we need you to
come down to the station.
그리고 선생님은 서에
가주셨으면 합니다
If you can't make
arrangements for your child,
아이를 돌봐줄 사람이 없으시면
we have a child services
advocate who can take him.
아이를 데려갈 아동 복지사를
데려오겠습니다
This is ridiculous.
I've been nothing but cooperative.
이건 말도 안 돼요
협조해드린 것뿐인데
You harass me at my place of work.
You harass me at my home.
직장에서 괴롭히고
집에서도 괴롭히는군요
Now you want to take my kid away?
이제는 아이까지 데려가겠다고요?
Sir, are you resisting?
선생님, 저항하시는 겁니까?
I didn't kill my wife.
난 아내를 죽이지 않았어요
I was giving my son a bath.
I couldn't have done it.
아들을 씻겨주고 있었어요
제가 죽이는 건 불가능했다고요
Can I at least put my shoes on?
신발은 신을 수 있는 거죠?
What have you got?
뭐 찾았어?
A smoking gun.
확실한 증거요
You're not going to like the answer.
결과과 별로 탐탁치 않을 거예요
The DNA on the cigarette
butts doesn't match Natal.
담배 꽁초에 있던 DNA는
나탈과 일치하지 않았어요
Come on.
말도 안 돼요
You can't tell me we're back
to square one on this deal.
수사가 원점으로 돌아갔다는
뜻은 아니겠죠?
Well, we're not.
음, 그건 아니에요
Dna was female,
so I ran it against Amanda, thinking,
DNA는 여성의 것이었어요
그래서 아만다랑 비교해봤어요
I don't know, maybe she takes
super secret cigarette breaks.
그게, 아만다가 아주 몰래 담배를
피울지도 모르겠다고 생각해서요
And it wasn't a match,
but they do have seven ??? in common.
아만다의 것이 아니었지만, 아만다랑
일곱 개의 유전형질이 일치했어요
So, is there another sister maybe?
그럼, 혹시 다른 자매가 있나요?
Tiffany.
티파니
I'm confused.
정말 황당하네요
This is 'cause I was smoking?
여기 온 게 제가
담배를 피워서예요?
Well, no, smoking is bad for you,
그건 아니야, 담배는
네 건강에 안 좋긴 하지만
but, no, this is really more
about where you were smoking.
이건 네가 어디서
담배를 피웠느냐는 문제야
I'm an only child
전 외동딸이에요
who lives on a horse farm
in the middle of nowhere
허허벌판에 있는 말 농장에 살아요
with a horse-whispering mother and
a dad who works all the time to avoid her.
말하고 이야기하는 엄마랑 그런 엄마를
피하려고 항상 일만 하는 아버지랑요
When Amanda's letter came...
아만다의 편지가 왔을 땐...
I was so excited at the idea of having a sister.
언니가 생긴다는 생각에
완전 들떴어요
I was jumping out of my skin.
기뻐서 펄쩍 뛸 정도였어요
So I told my mom i joined Cheerleading.
엄마에게는 응원연습한다고 말하고
And after school, I would...
방과 후에 가곤 했어요...
You'd what?
뭘 했다고?
It started where I would just drive by.
그냥 차를 타고
지나가기 시작했어요
And then it escalated? / Well...
그리고나서 정도가 더
심해진 거니? / 그건...
Once I saw her in the yard,
playing with her little boy.
한 번은 마당에서 아이랑
놀고 있는 언니를 봤어요
So I started parking out front.
그래서 집 앞에 주차를 했죠
Hoping to see her again.
다시 한 번 보고 싶어서요
Basically, I would just sit there,
imagining her in my life.
그저, 거기 앉아서 언니가 있는
내 인생을 상상했어요
She'd make me tea.
제게 차를 타주고요
And we'd go over my college
applications and talk about boys.
제 대학지원서를 같이 검토하고
남자친구 얘기도 하는 걸 말이에요
It was like a TV commercial.
TV 광고 같은 상상이었죠
And then what?
Did your...
그리고 나서는 어떻게 했니?
너의 그 ...
curiosity...become an obsession?
호기심이... 집착이 된 거니?
Oh, my god.
오, 이런
No.
아뇨
I could barely get up the
courage to introduce myself.
전 절 소개할 용기도 없었어요
That's why I'd just sit there smoking.
그게 거기 앉아서
담배를 피운 이유예요
And then my stomach would hurt,
so I would just drive home.
그러고 나서 배가 아파서
그냥 집으로 왔어요
And now, I'll never get the chance.
이제 그런 기회를
가질 수도 없네요
Jill
질
Hey, Grissom said you
might need some help.
선배, 반장님이 도와주라고 하셔서 왔어요
What? / I don't know, you don't look
like you've been put through the ringer.
왜요? / 글쎄, 네가 힘든 상황을
겪은 사람처럼 보이질 않아
Well, I guess the inquest
was the easy part.
제 생각엔 심리는
그래도 쉬운 거였어요
Now the kid's family wants to sue me.
이제 드미트리의 가족이
절 고소하길 원하거든요
Know any good lawyers?
좋은 변호사 아세요?
I hate lawyers.
난 변호사들이 싫어
Want to take the bathroom?
욕실 좀 맡아줄래?
Sure.
그러죠
I found her naughty drawer.
얌전하지 못한 서랍을 찾았어
My favorite part of any bedroom search.
제가 침실 조사에서
제일 좋아하는 부분이죠
I don't believe these girls anymore.
난 이런 여자들
더는 못 믿겠어
Looks like someone's been
elevated to drawer status.
서랍을 두고 사용할 만큼
친밀한 사람이 있는 것 같아
Well, apparently,
love can't cure all that ills.
음, 분명 사랑이 모든 병을
치료해 줄 순 없죠
Alprazolam, clonazepam,
diazepam and sertraline.
알프라졸람, 클로나제팜, 다이아제팜
설트랄린(진정제, 항우울제)
all in her medicine cabinet.
전부 약장 안에 있었어요
Well, I said dude had a drawer,
I didn't say it was love.
서랍을 가진 사내가 있다고 했지
사랑이라고 말한 적은 없는데
Jill had OCD-related depression,
질은 강박장애성 우울증이 있었어요
which is very deceiving because
the sufferers are high functioning.
환자들이 할 일을 잘하기 때문에
아주 속아 넘어가기 쉬운 병이죠
It's not your usual, you know,
그러니까, 이 우울증은
“lie on the couch and listen
to the Beatles" kind of depression.
"소파에 누워 비틀즈 음악이나 듣고 있는"
평범한 우울증은 아니에요
Did she ever talk about family?
질이 가족에 대해 얘기하던가요?
You know, when a patient dies,
아시다시피, 환자가 죽으면
the doctor-patient
confidentiality clause is void.
의사와 환자 사이의 비밀보장
조항이 무효가 되긴 하지만
But I'm just sort of feeling
a little uncomfortable.
그래도 좀 껄끄럽습니다
Do I have to call a lawyer?
제가 변호사를 불러야 할까요?
It's entirely your choice.
전적으로 박사님 맘입니다
We can subpoena her records,
or you and I can talk.
질의 기록에 대해 영장을 발부하든지
아님 박사님께서 말씀해 주시든지요
Okay. All she would say was that she
didn't get along with her parents,
좋아요. 질이 얘기한 거라곤
부모님과 잘 지내지 못하며
and that, you know,
relationships in general were difficult.
전반적인 인간 관계가 어렵게
느껴진다는 말뿐이었어요
I mean, her condition made her
excel professionally but flop personally.
직업적으론 우수했지만 사생활적으로는
실패할 수밖에 없었던 상황이었다는 거죠
We, checked her records.
질의 기록을 조사해 봤는데
She was adopted as an infant.
태어난 지 얼마 안 돼서
입양되었더군요
Her parents never told her.
질의 양부모가 질에게
사실을 숨긴 거군요
Well, that explains her
abandonment/attachment issues,
음, 그게 질의 유기/애착 문제를
설명해 주는군요
and why she always felt like a
square peg in a round family.
질이 왜 항상 가족들과 겉돈다고
느꼈는지도 이해가 되고요
Did you believe she was suicidal?
질이 자살을 했을 거라 생각하십니까?
Off the record, no, I don't.
I don't think she was suicidal, I thought,
개인적으론, 아닙니다
자살할 사람은 아닌 것 같아요
I actually thought she was getting better.
사실은 질이 좋아지고 있다고
생각했거든요
So then how does an attractive,
successful 36-year-old woman
그럼 어떻게 매력적이고
성공한 36세의 여성이
hang herself from her own balcony?
자기 집 발코니에서
목을 맨 걸까요?
'Cause the choice was there.
그 선택을 할 수밖에
없었기 때문이죠
At the end of the day, when an obsessive
brain is presented with a choice,
결국, 두뇌가 어떤 선택을 해야 한다는
강박관념에 일단 사로잡히게 되면
it just sometimes, it just can't shut off
두뇌는 때때로, 이유 없이
the clatter of the idea until it
sees it through to conclusion.
결론을 맺기 전까진 그 생각을
떨칠 수가 없게 되어서
The idea found its way in.
그 생각을 실행에 옮기게 되죠
It wasn't suicide.
자살이 아니었어
These bruises developed postmortem.
이 멍들이 사후에 나타났어
Two on the front, eight on the back.
앞에 두 개, 뒤에 여덟 개야
Strangulation.
교살이네요
Murder.
살인이야
No, she missed the
morning news meeting,
아뇨, 아침 회의에
안 나오셨어요
all the section editors
are biting my head off.
모든 부서 편집장들이
저한테 화를 내고 있어요
Look, I don't have a
straight answer for you.
정확한 답변을 드릴 수가 없어요
No, I've called, I've e-mailed, I've texted.
아뇨, 전화하고, 이메일도 보내고
문자도 보냈어요
She'd have to be lying dead in a
ditch not to answer her phone.
전화를 안 받는 걸 보니
도랑에라도 빠져 죽었나 봐요
I know. Bye.
Can I help you?
알았어요. 끊을게요
도와드릴까요?
I'm detective Jim Brass,
Las Vegas police.
라스베가스 경찰
짐 브래스 형사입니다
This is Warrick Brown from the crime lab.
이쪽은 과학수사대 워릭 브라운이고요
We have a warrant to
search Jill Case's office.
질 케이스 씨의 사무실
수색 영장을 가지고 왔습니다
Okay, is she in some kind of trouble?
알았어요, 국장님께
무슨 문제라도 생겼나요?
Well, it wasn't a ditch.
음, 도랑이 아니었습니다
Oh, my god.
오, 이런
God.
이런
What's going on?
무슨 일이에요?
Back off. Get away.
All of you, go! Go!
저리 가세요. 저리 가라고요
전부 다요, 가세요! 가요!
Look, you can't drop a hot
one in a room full of vultures.
독수리로 득실대는 여기에
싱싱한 먹잇감을 던지시면 어떡해요
They smell blood.
저 사람들은 피냄새를 맡는단 말이에요
Half of them were wanting to pry
her ass out of that chair for months.
저 사람들 중 반은 몇 달째
국장님의 자리를 노리고 있거든요
I'll need a list of all the employees
who work for the paper.
신문사에서 일하는 모든 직원의
명단이 필요합니다
Can you provide that?
명단을 주실 수 있습니까?
I don't have access to that kind of information.
그런 정보를 열람할 권한이
제겐 없어요
You're gonna have to go
down to human resources.
인사과에 내려가 보셔야 할 거예요
Human resources. Okay.
인사과라
알았습니다
You're on your own.
자네가 알아서 하게
I'll be taking a look inside her office, okay?
질의 사무실을 좀 둘러보겠습니다
Did Jill have a computer?
질이 컴퓨터를 가지고 있었나요?
Yeah, her laptop, of course.
It was like an extra limb.
네, 물론이에요. 노트북이었죠
항상 끼고 사셨어요
- What's with the locked drawer?
- That was a new thing.
- 이 서랍은 왜 잠겨 있죠?
- 최근 들어 잠그시더군요
She's always been neurotic,
but lately she's been secretive, like sneaky.
항상 예민하신 분이긴 했지만
최근에 뭔가 숨기는 게 있는 것 같았어요
Rolling her own calls,
making her own appointments,
직접 전화를 거시고
직접 약속을 잡으셨거든요
talking with editors from other newspapers.
다른 신문사 편집장들이랑
말씀하시면서요
Honestly, I just thought she
was looking for another job.
솔직히 말하면, 국장님이
직장을 옮기시는 줄 알았어요
Did you ever try to open this drawer?
이거 열어보신 적 있습니까?
Are you kidding?
무슨 말씀이세요?
She had the only key, and protecting
her privacy was how I kept my job.
열쇠는 국장님이 가지고 계시고
제 일은 국장님 사생활을 보호하는 거예요
Because Amanda's murder is still unsolved,
아직 아만다의 사건이 미해결이라서
I cross-checked the twin address books.
쌍둥이의 주소록을
서로 비교해 봤는데요
Now, they have no
contacts in common, but...
그 두 쌍둥이가 만날
일은 없어요, 그런데...
there are a couple freaky things.
몇 가지 좀 이상한 게 있어요
So Amanda was set to pick up
dry cleaning in the morning,
아만다는 아침에 세탁소에 가서
옷을 찾아오기로 했는데
but it looks as though
she had a sick child,
아이가 아파서 대신
so she went at night instead. / Right.
- 저녁에 간 것 같네
- 맞아요
And if she'd gone earlier
than she was supposed to,
그리고 만약 원래 가려던
시간에 갔더라면요
she might've run into Jill,
질을 만났을지도 몰라요
who was scheduled to pick up
her dry cleaning at 8:30 in the morning.
질은 오전 8시 반에 세탁물을
가지러 가기로 되어 있었는데
But it gets better.
지금부터가 더 흥미로워요
Based on receipts from Amanda's planner
and quicken listings from Jill's Treo,
아만다의 다이어리와
질의 PDA 일정목록을 살펴보면
they used the same dry cleaner,
same car dealership,
같은 세탁소에
같은 카센터를 이용했고
they both had a weakness for the
same frozen yogurt and blended mochas,
두 사람 모두 같은 냉동 요구르트와
모카 커피를 좋아했어요
and in two weeks, Jill was
scheduled to teach a university
그리고 질은 2주일 뒤에
사진 촬영 공개강좌를
extension class in photography.
대학에서 강의할 예정이었어요
Guess who was signed up to take the class?
누가 이 강좌에 등록했을 거 같아요?
Amanda. / Huh.
아만다 / 허
They would've finally met.
결국엔 만났겠군
So having the same toe nail polish and watch
둘이 아는 사이라고 생각했을 땐
두 사람이 같은 매니큐어랑
made sense when we thought they
knew each other, but now?
같은 시계를 차고 있는 게
말이 됐는데, 지금은요?
I mean, they even have
almost the same handwriting.
그러니까, 이 사람들
필체도 거의 같아요
Well, people's first explanation
with twins is always parapsychology,
항상 사람들은 쌍둥이를 설명할 때
가장 먼저 초심리학을 이용하지
but the truth is, there's a lot
of biological encoding at work.
그러나 사실은 많은 생물학적
요인들이 영향을 미친다는 거야
I mean, if you have the same
musculature and bone structure in your hand,
그러니까 손에 있는
근육 조직이랑 골격이 같으면
the chance of writing the
same is not out of the question.
같은 필체를 갖는 게
불가능한 것도 아니지
If beauty is in the eye of the beholder,
아름다움을 구별하는 것이
제 눈에 안경이라면
and you both see with the same eyes
or taste with the same tongue.
쌍둥이는 같은 눈으로 보고
같은 혀로 맛을 보는 거지
Well, I don't know whose eyes
she was using for this guy.
이 남자를 만날 땐 누구의 눈을
사용했는지 모르겠네요
Jill was scheduled to have dinner
at Joie de Vive on the night she died.
질이 죽은 날 저녁에 조아 드 비브에서
식사할 예정이었어요
So Warrick called over and
got the surveillance footage.
그래서 워릭 선배가 전화해서
감시 카메라 영상을 가져왔는데
I don't have an ID yet.
누군지는 아직 모르겠어요
I do.
나는 알아
Her relationship with me was the
most intimate she's ever had.
저와 질의 관계는 질이 가졌던
관계 중 가장 친밀한 거였어요
I actually felt like we were making progress.
사실 서로 진전이 있다고 생각했어요
Until the murder.
살인을 하기 전까지는요
What are you talking about?
무슨 말씀을 하시는 겁니까?
She committed suicide.
질은 자살했습니다
Did I tell you that?
제가 그렇게 말했던가요?
What are you, what are you suggesting,
that I murdered my own patient?
무슨 말을, 무슨 말씀이시죠
내가 내 환자를 죽였단 겁니까?
Let me run down the sequence of events.
제가 사건을 순서대로
한번 말해볼게요
So you took your "girlfriend" out to dinner.
당신은 '당신 여자친구'를
데리고 나가 저녁식사를 했고
Then you brought her home
for a little tie me up, tie me down.
집에 데리고 와선 서로
묶어주는 놀이를 한 거죠
But things get wonky and
in the throes of passion,
하지만 일이 꼬이기 시작했고
한창 정욕이 달아올랐을 때
you remembered, "wait a minute,
she's a patient, uh-oh."
갑자기 생각났겠지, "잠깐
이 여잔 환자잖아, 이런"하고 말이요
So she had a history of depression.
So you used that knowledge to cover it up.
그래서 질에겐 우울증 병력이 있었으니까
살인을 은폐하려고 그걸 사용한 거죠
Well, we did go to dinner that night,
but afterwards I dropped her off.
저녁식사를 함께 한 건 사실이지만
나중에 집까지 태워 주고 그냥 왔어요
Because she said she had to work to do.
질이 할 일이 있다고 했거든요
I didn't even go inside,
so I don't even understand your question.
전 집안에 들어가지도 않았답니다
그래서 형사님 질문을 이해할 수가 없습니다
Are you saying the two of
you never had rough sex?
그럼 두 분이 거친 섹스를
하신 적이 없다는 겁니까?
Now, be careful here, doctor.
조심하는 게 좋을 거요, 의사 선생
Yeah, it's true that, in the past,
we engaged in some,
예, 옛날에 그런 걸
좀 했던 건 사실이에요
you know, some, role playing sex games
to help get her comfortable, but...
질을 편안하게 해주려고 섹스
역할극 같은 걸 했었죠, 하지만...
But what?
하지만 뭐요?
She was the "S," I was the "M."
질이 S였고 내가 M이었어요
(S : Sadist-가학, M : Masochist-피학)
Hey, um...
있잖아요, 음...
You know, how we thought that
the shrink was a slam dunk
질을 목 졸라 죽이고
목을 매단 범인은
for Jill's strangulation hanging combo?
정신과 의사가 확실하다고
생각하고 있는 거죠?
Yeah. / Well, I ran his DNA against
the epithelials we found on the leash.
네 / 제가 그 의사의 DNA를 줄에서
발견된 상피세포랑 비교해 봤는데요
And the epithelials are male,
but they're not his.
상피세포가 남성의 것이긴 하지만
정신과 의사의 것은 아니었어요
Thanks.
고마워요
News on our case.
새로운 소식이에요
The shrink might not have done it?
정신과 의사가 범인이
아닐지도 모른다고?
How did you know?
어떻게 아셨어요?
Because Archie found
us another strong suspect.
아치가 유력한 용의자를
또 한 명 찾았거든
You know, that flash drive that I found in
the locked drawer in Jill case's office,
내가 질 사무실의 잠긴 서랍 안에서
발견한 플래시 드라이브 말이야
I thought it was just a bunch of photos
그냥 여러 장의 사진이라고만
생각했는데
but it turns out there was a
little bit more than meets the eye.
그런데, 눈에 보이는 게
전부가 아니더라고
You mean the flash drive was a transformer?
플래시 드라이브가 로봇처럼
변신이라도 했다는 거예요?
No. / Well, the pictures kind of were.
아니 / 사진들이 좀 변신했죠
Check it out.
Look familiar?
이것 좀 봐
눈에 익지?
This got bought by the A.P.
A.P 통신에서 사들인 사진으로
It was on the front page
of the Las Vegas Globe.
라스베가스 글로브지의
제1면에 실렸었고
It won a Pulitzer.
It was everywhere.
퓰리처 상도 탔고
사방에 널려 있는 사진이야
Okay. So what?
알았어요. 그래서요?
These are Jake Lenoir's
photographs taken in Iraq last summer.
이 사진들은 지난 여름 이라크에서
제이크 르노아가 찍은 거야
Watch this.
이걸 좀 보세요
The front page news was
actually a composite?
제1면 기사가 사실은
합성이었다고요?
Well, it's a...
음, 그게...
essentially an art project.
본질적으론 예술 작품인 거죠
And Jill printed it.
그리고 질이 출력했어
I assume she didn't
realize it until it was too late.
질이 알아차렸을 때는
이미 너무 늦어버렸던 거고
And before she died, she was
trying to figure out how to handle it.
죽기 전에, 어떻게 처리해야 할지
방법을 모색하고 있었을 거야
The only thing standing between Jake
and the rest of his career was the truth.
제이크의 남은 생애에
유일한 걸림돌은 진실이었군요
And Jill case.
그리고 질 케이스였지
It must be fun to be you.
그것 참 재밌겠습니다
Got a job that takes you around the world,
전 세계를 돌아다니는 직업에
get to meet some great girls,
멋진 여자들도 만날 수 있고
even win some awards.
게다가 상까지 타고 말입니다
So why would an adrenaline junkie like you,
당신처럼 스릴을 좋아하는 사람이
waste his time with Photoshopping?
왜 포토샵질을 하며
시간을 낭비했을까요?
Let me tell you something that the,
얘기 하나 해드리죠
newspapers, tv stations don't want to hear.
신문사나 방송국에선
듣고 싶어하지 않는 얘기지만
There's nothing over there to photograph.
거기엔 찍을 만한 게 없어요
Insurgents?
반란군들이요?
They fire off their outdated
weapons then run the other way.
반란군들은 구식 무기를
쏘고는 도망가는 게 전부죠
When we do midnight raids in the villages,
you know what the people tell us?
우리가 마을을 야간에 습격하면
사람들이 뭐라고 하는지 아십니까?
"Alibaba not here."
"알리바바는 여기 없어요"
We are fighting a fictional character.
우리는 가상의 인물과
싸우는 겁니다
And you got thousands of
soldiers over there, kids,
18살 먹은 아이들로 구성된
수천 명의 병사가 그곳에서
18 years old, pumped up on testosterone,
full of nicotine, and caffeine,
스테로이드를 과다 복용하고
니코틴과 카페인에 쩔어서
waiting for some
thing to bloody well happen.
실제로 무슨 일이 생기길
바라고 있죠
And you know what?
You pray for a roadside bomb
그거 아세요?
액션 장면을 보고 싶어서
because it feels like action.
도로에 매설된 폭탄이
터지길 바랍니다
But you can't photograph
the taste of gasoline.
하지만 휘발유 맛을
사진에 담을 수는 없죠
It just looks like smoke.
그냥 연기 같아 보일 뿐이죠
So one day, yeah,
I'm screwing around on my computer.
그래서, 하루는 제 컴퓨터를
가지고 빈둥거리고 있었는데
Couple of soldiers come by,
took a look at what I'm doing.
병사 몇 명이 와서는
제가 하고 있던 작업을 보더군요
You know what they say?
그 병사들이 뭐라고 했는지 아세요?
They say, "yeah, yeah, that's our war.
"맞아, 맞아
저게 바로 전쟁이지"
That's what it's like waiting and body hauling."
"기다림과 시체 운반 같은 것 말이야"
So I had it. I had the
image that said it all.
그래서 만들었죠. 모든 걸
말해주는 그 사진을 말입니다
So yes.
맞아요
I used a lie to tell the truth.
전 진실을 말하려고
거짓말을 한 겁니다
Well, thanks for the insight.
훌륭한 얘기 잘 들었습니다
But I'm looking for another
kind of confession.
제가 듣고 싶은 고백은
따로 있습니다
I'm here to bust you for
the murder of Jill Case.
전 질 케이스를 살해한 혐의로
당신을 체포하러 온 겁니다
What? / Come on,
she was hip to your, uh,
뭐라고요? / 보세요
질은 당신의 사진이
you know cut and paste scheme and
she was going to blow the whistle on you.
오려내고 붙여서 만든 사진이란 걸
알고나서 그걸 폭로하려 했던 거죠
Yeah, yeah, yeah, well, I heard
she committed suicide and look...
아, 그거 말입니까, 나도 질이
자살했다는 말은 들었어요...
oh, is that what you heard? / Yeah.
오, 정말 그렇게
들으셨나요? / 네
Me and her, we,
we had a history, okay. We dated.
저랑 질, 우린 서로
사귀었고 데이트도 했어요
But if she felt like outing me for this all I
had to do was accuse
하지만 질이 이 일을 폭로하려 했다면
전 질을 성적 확대로 고소해야 했을걸요
her of sexual harassment
and we both go down.
그럼 우리 둘 다 끝나는 거죠
Maybe ethical journalism
was worth the price for her.
질은 자신을 희생할 만큼
언론 윤리가 가치 있다고 생각했겠죠
Doubtful.
아닐 거예요
Without her job, she had nothing.
질은 직업 말곤 아무것도
가진 게 없는 여자였으니까요
Well, for a while, she had you.
뭐, 잠깐이지만
당신이 있었잖소
Yeah, but not for long.
그렇죠, 그런데
오래가진 못했어요
Bird was rigid in everything she did.
모든 일에 딱딱한 여자였거든요
Having sex with her
was like... eating glass.
질과 섹스를 하는 건 마치
유리조각을 삼키는 것 같았죠
The lab did a DNA test
연구소에서 DNA 검사를 했는데
your skin cells are all over the
dog leash that was used to hang her.
질을 목매달 때 쓴 개 줄에서 당신의
상피세포가 대량으로 검출됐어요
Well, I was probably the last
person to actually walk that dog.
아마도 제가 마지막으로
개를 산책시켜줬을 겁니다
God knows she never did.
질은 단 한 번도
산책시킨 적이 없어요
Guess this is more like his crash
pad between foreign assignments.
여긴 집이라기보단
해외근무 때 묵는 참호 같군요
I'm sorry, I just don't see miss neat knickers
and this guy making it as a couple.
미안, 그냥 그 '깔끔' 양과 이 자식이
사귀었다는 게 이해가 안 돼
Still no laptop.
노트북은 여전히 안 보여
- Steal it, scrub it and lose it.
- This guy's smart.
- 훔쳐서, 지우고, 버려라
- 영리한 녀석이군
This is all just circumstantial.
전부 정황 증거뿐이야
Now we know how he got
her to write the suicide note.
질에게 어떻게 유서를
쓰게 했는지 알겠어
She wasn't sorry to be living.
질은 살아있는 게
미안한 게 아니었어
She was sorry that Jake was such a liar.
제이크가 거짓말한 게
미안했던 거지
Well, this is more like what we need.
우리가 찾아야 했던 건
오히려 이것 같네요
Warrick.
선배
Didn't Nick's case have a
blue thigh high stocking?
닉 선배 사건에서
파란색 스타킹이 발견됐죠?
Yeah.
응
Even if he was the one that strangled Jill,
there was no blood at the crime scene.
질을 목졸라 죽인 게 제이크라고 해도
범죄 현장에 혈흔은 없었어
Well, with two gunshots to the chest,
그래도, 가슴에 총상이 두 개면
Jill's twin sister was a bloody mess.
질의 쌍둥이 자매는
피투성이였을 거예요
Checkmate?
딱 걸렸죠?
So he killed them both.
제이크가 두 사람을 다 죽였군
You must have thought
you were losing your mind?
정신이 나갔는 줄 알았죠?
Let me run it for you.
설명해 드리죠
Jill always picked up her dry
cleaning on Thursday nights.
질은 항상 목요일 저녁에
세탁물을 찾으러 갔죠
So right place, right time, right car,
그러니, 정확한 장소
정확한 시간, 정확한 차
looks like the right woman.
정확한 여자처럼 보였죠
You thought it was done.
당신은 다 끝났다고
생각했겠죠
So you go to the house,
get the computer files
그래서 질의 집으로 가서
컴퓨터 파일을 찾아냈고
and you think you're seeing your
conscious walk through the door.
그리고 누군가 문을 열고 들어오는 걸
봤지만 유령일거라 생각한거죠
Don't touch me...
만지지 마
The first time you had a plan.
Try to make it look like a mugging.
첫 번째는 범행을 계획한 거였고
강도처럼 보이게 할 생각이었죠
The second time, you had to improvise.
두 번째는 즉흥적으로 해야만 했죠
So there were two of them.
그럼 두 명이 있었다는 거군요
I dated Jill.
질하고 사귀었어요
She kept the most rigid schedule
of anyone I've ever met, you know.
질은 제가 만났던 여자들 중에 스케줄을
가장 철저하게 지켰던 여자였어요
It was always Thursday
night pick up the dry cleaning night.
세탁물을 찾아오는 건
항상 목요일 밤이었어요
And I mean, god forbid I wanted to see
a movie or catch a show or something.
그러니까 영화든, 공연이든
뭐가 됐든 절대로 볼 수 없었죠
Leave it to Jill to be so thorough.
질의 철저함을
너무 믿은 거죠
Makes me have to kill her twice.
그게 질을 두 번
죽이게 만든 거군요
We were both right.
우리 둘 다 맞았어요
That's a federal offense, you know.
그거 연방법 위반이야
I heard the guys solved
a double murder. / Mm hmm.
- 이중 살인사건을 해결했다면서요
- 그래
I spent the day sitting on a bench outside
the courtroom, they never got to me.
전 법정 밖에서 하루종일 앉아 있었어요
제 순서는 오지 않았어요
That sucks.
짜증났겠군
- Feeling transcendental?
- Hmm?
- 초월적인 게 느껴져요?
- 흠?
Thoreau. I, I haven't read him since college.
소로우, 대학을 졸업하고 나선
읽은 적이 없어요
Me, neither.
It holds up.
나도 그래
지금도 읽을 만해
"I would rather sit on a
pumpkin and have it all to myself,
"넓고 화려한 집에서 여러 사람과
함께 사느니, 난 차라리
than be crowded on a velvet cushion."
작고 초라한 집이지만
내 집에서 혼자서 살리라"
Oh, look, you missed one.
Sixty-three down.
오, 여기 하나 못 풀었네요
세로 63번이요
Misanthrope.
Misanthrope(인간혐오)네요
I won't wait up.
빨리 안 오시면
먼저 잘 거예요
번역수정
황성규(hscent70@nate.com)
한글수정
안은정(actwo@nate.com)
자막제작 - 네이트 CSI 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/clubcsi)